A young and ambitious entrepreneur, passionate about programming and Computer Science. I have experience working as a Software Engineer at small and big companies like Microsoft. I recently developed Wrumer, an app/device, and built an e-commerce business around it, doing approximately €30k in monthly sales. I was active in the open-source community and have made significant contributions to projects like Yarn.

Education

King's College London, BSc in Computer Science

London, United Kingdom

Graduated with a First Class Honours.

2019 - 2022

• Gained programming experience in Java, AVR Assembly, C++, Ruby, and JavaScript.

Gimnazija Bezigrad, Secondary School

Ljubljana, Slovenia

• Graduated with honors (top 5% of national graduating class).

2014 - 2018

Professional Experience

Microsoft, Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom

• Working on the Microsoft Teams product.

2022 - Present

- Extensively worked with Java, Electron, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, and CSS in JS.
- Got closely familiar with "Continuous testing & deployment" and product management using ADO.

WrumerSound, Founder and CEO

2022 - Present

- WrumerSound is an E-commerce business where I developed a device that simulates engine sounds through the car's speakers.
- I have sold around 5,000 units (€200,000 revenue) and am still doing around €30k in monthly sales.
- As a sole founder, I had to develop the company from the ground up. Among other things, I had to:
 - · Design and develop the Wrumer device and app.
 - Find a manufacturer and set up the distribution logistics.
 - Design, develop, and maintain the company web store.
- The Wrumer app is compatible with iOS and Android and is written in **React Native**.
- I wrote an audio engine in **FMOD** and integrated it into the app using **Native Modules**.
- Graphed and analyzed the data coming from the car using **Python**.
- Learn more about it at: https://wrumersound.com/

Freelancer Ljubljana, Slovenia

Designed and built numerous websites and online stores.

2021 - 2022

- Extensively worked with JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJS, CSS in JS, and Shopify.
- Some of the projects I worked on:
 - ROSE INC https://www.roseinc.co.uk/
 - JVN Hair https://jvnhair.com/
 - EGGO https://www.eggoglow.com/

Amondo Ltd., Full-stack web developer

London, United Kingdom

• Designed and built several web products using a modern web stack.

2018 - 2021

- · Extensively worked with:
 - Front-end: JavaScript (ES5 & ES6), TypeScript, Babel, Webpack, ReactJS, CSS in JS;
 - Back-end: NodeJS, RESTful APIs (Express, CORS), GraphQL APIs, Database (PostgreSQL);
 - General: Source Control (Git), Unit & E2E testing (jest, puppeteer, cypress), Continuous testing & deployment (CircleCl, Heroku).

More on the next page.

Projects

PhoneFly, Facebook Instant Game (down because of FB policy changes)

- Built a game with **75.000 unique users** the objective of which is to throw your phone as high as possible.
- Developed an algorithm that determines the height of the throw, based on the phone's internal sensors.
- Core technologies/concepts used: HTML, CSS in JS, TypeScript, ReactJS.
- Source code: <u>github.com/juresotosek/phonefly</u>.

ActivityTracker, Slack App

- A Slack app that allows you to track who and when is online in your Slack workspace.
- Core technologies/concepts used:
 - Front-end: HTML, CSS in JS, TypeScript, ReactJS, NextJS;
 - Back-end: NodeJS (Next.js), Database (Prisma, Postgres).
 - General: Continuous testing & deployment (CircleCl, Heroku)
- Website: https://www.activitytracker.dev/.

meni.io, QR code menus

- · Co-founded a company that builds digital menus for restaurants and bars.
- Built a full-stack web solution for creating and presenting QR Code menus that served over 100k customers.
- · Core technologies/concepts used:
 - Front-end: HTML, CSS in JS, TypeScript, ReactJS;
 - Back-end: NodeJS (Next.js), Database (Prisma, Postgres).
 - General: Continuous testing & deployment (CircleCl, Vercel)

Open Source

Yarn, Package Manager

- Implemented an interactive search command that simplifies the way users find packages.
- One of the core JavaScript developer tools with over 60 million total downloads.
- Core technologies/concepts used: NodeJS, TypeScript.
- Website: https://yarnpkg.com, the implemented feature: github.com/yarnpkg/berry/pull/1425.

Other contributions (click on the link to see my PRs):

- maticzav/emma-cli (~1.1k stars, ~4.9k downloads total);
- dotansimha/graphgl-code-generator (~3.5k stars, ~400k downloads per week);
- algolia/npm-search (~55 stars).

Interests and Activities

I enjoy sports. In 2015, I was a Slovenian national champion in short-distance hurdling.